Shreyas/Shey Garga

Data Analyst

CONTACT

PHONE

703-986-6648

MAIL

garga.shreyas@gmail.com

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/shreyasgarga

GITHUB

Sheygarga

TECHNOLOGY

PYTHON

SQL

HTML/CSS

JAVASCRIPT

MACHINE LEARNING/BIG DATA

ADVANCED EXCEL

JAVA

SKILLS

- DATA WRANGLING
- GRAPHING/CHARTING
- SOCIAL MEDIA MINING
- SQL/NoSQL (MONGODB) APP BUILDING
- WEB SCRAPING
- WEB DEVELOPMENT
- GEO MAPPING
- INTERACTIVE VISUALIZATION
- STATISTICAL ANALYSIS WITH R
- TABLEAU/POWERBI

Summary

Driven data analyst with a Bachelor's in Neuroscience and experience in business and social analytics. Has created numerous automated and responsive data analytics applications and solutions to identify, analyze, and interpret trends and patterns. Excellent research and analytical skills. Gamer, Twitch streamer, guitarist, and black belt in Tae Kwon Do.

Projects

My time at George Washington University has given me experience in full stack development of data analytic applications and solutions to make decisions, identify areas of improvement, and explore data for insight. Learnt the following technologies:

Python	Pandas, Numpy, SciPy, MatPlotLib APIs, Tweepy, Vader, Seaborn, PySpark
Database	SQL and noSQL databases such as MySQL and MongoDB and manipulated them with
	SQLAlchemy and Flask for web-scraping
Web	HTML, CSS and Javascript frameworks such as: Bootstrap, Plotly, ChartJS, JQuery, D3, Node,
	Agile, React, Leaflet, Carto
Big Data	TensorFlow, Spark, Hadoop, NLP, MRJob, Keras, SKLearn,

My projects include:

- Python analysis of the Thomas Fire and the social media sentiment around Los Angeles
- Pandas data analysis for provided CSV files
- Live updating dataframe and graph for news sentiment analysis
- Live updating SQL app that can isolate vacation dates for Hawaii based on weather averages
- Web dashboard based on the global weather averages using Javascript, HTML, and Bootstrap
- Heroku-deployed app for analysis on given dataset alongside a resting API using Javascript.
- Responsive d3 and plot.ly based Javascript dashboard to show citation data for journalism
- Live updating, Heroku-deployed, Python and Javascript-based web app to display information about solar energy and skin cancer rates at the state level.

Employment

Behavioral Care Services

Gainesville, VA

Office Manager

June 2010 – April 2018

- Developed company web site, implemented search engine optimization. Responsible for website traffic analysis and google AdWords optimization.
- Established the processes for scheduling, collaboration and document sharing using Google applications
- Maintain and support network, hardware and software at the office.
- Handle operations of the practice including communicating with clients and insurance companies

Garga Insurance

Centreville, VA

Social Media Coordinator

January 2018 – April 2018

- $\bullet \qquad \text{Manage social media marketing using outlets such as Facebook, Tweeter, LinkedIn etc.}\\$
- Generate and/or find pertinent information and pictures to post content.
- Responsible for promoting posts and increasing online visibility

Shimla Medical Center

Manassas, VA

Intern and Assistant

October 2016 – March 2017

- Preparatory work such as taking vitals and retrieving reports for the doctor
- Post-patient meetings to learn the diagnosis process
- Building rapport with regular and new patients to help them feel comfortable

Education

George Washington University

Data Analyst/Data Visualization Bootcamp

October 2017 - April 2018

George Mason University

BS of Neuroscience

August 2013- December 2017